<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome on IDEAlab</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on IDEAlab</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://idealab.asu.edu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Foldable Robotics Day Camp 2024</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/events/foldable-robotics-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/events/foldable-robotics-2024/</guid><description>Unfortunately, we will not be able to hold the camp this summer. Please check back in Spring 2025</description></item><item><title>SCRAMS: Soft, Curved, Reconfigurable, Anisotropic Mechanisms</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/efri/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/efri/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Soft Curved Reconfigurable Anisotropic Mechanisms (SCRAMs) are a new class of soft robotic technology that will enable new multi-functional soft robots with reconfigurable actuation and shapes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key to the proposed technology is the ability to change the mechanical properties of a thin-walled structure by changing its local curvature. For example, curving a flat sheet of paper along one direction greatly increases its stiffness in the other two directions. Exploiting the coupling between curvature and mechanical behavior in planar materials will enable the design, modeling, and control of reconfigurable soft robots. Based on this concept, we have proposed two different models made from soft materials that can all be used to alter the mechanical behavior via tuning the structural stiffness. These three models are thin-walled cylindrical tubes, and curve beams.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CAREER: Dynamic Modeling and Fabrication of Compliant Material Systems for On-Demand Specialist Robots</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/career/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/career/</guid><description>&lt;div class="text-center">
&lt;img src="https://idealab.asu.edu/assets/images/research/career.png" alt>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This Faculty Early Career Development (CAREER) grant will make it possible to develop cost-effective, specialist robots that can be prototyped by a non-expert in a matter of hours. The goal of this project is to make robots more ubiquitous, accessible, and tunable for newcomers to robotics and for applications in industry, education, and academic research. Achieving this goal requires a shift towards more affordable materials, accessible fabrication strategies, and assistive design software that considers the particular dynamics of cost-efficient motors and materials, as well as the needs of specific applications. The results of this project will impact fields in which specialization is desirable, such as assistive robotics for the elderly, custom agricultural applications, and trash pickup in smart cities. The robots developed through this project will also serve as an affordable starting point for children to compete in after-school robotics competitions organized by local, youth-focused nonprofits. In addition, the models and templates developed for this project will be integrated into college-level robotics curricula, permitting students to venture deeper into advanced robotics topics earlier in their studies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foldable Robotics Day Camp 2023</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/events/foldable-robotics-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/events/foldable-robotics-2023/</guid><description>In this exciting hands-on, day camp, participants will be introduced to the principles of robot design through origami &amp;ndash; the art of paper folding &amp;ndash; to prototype, ideate, and get a hands-on sense of the physics of robots.</description></item><item><title>A Wearable Hybrid Robotic Suit for Self-Actualization and Well-Being</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/kaiteki/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/kaiteki/</guid><description>This project proposes a wearable hybrid robotic system to address mobility issues that occur in aging populations. The goal of this system will be to support and guide the wearer through every day tasks, improving stability to reduce the risk of falls and subsequent injury. Our approach takes a three-thrust approach: 1) understanding through human biomechanics studies where and how interventions on the human body can have the highest impact, 2) the design of a suit that reconfigures itself on demand to provide external load pathways to the ground while staying transparent to the wearer in other use-cases, and 3) decision on how to reconfigure and use the suit informed by predictive biomechanics and sensor fusion approaches.</description></item><item><title>Foldable Robotics Day Camp 2022</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/events/foldable-robotics-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/events/foldable-robotics-2022/</guid><description>In this exciting hands-on, day camp, participants will be introduced to the principles of robot design through origami &amp;ndash; the art of paper folding &amp;ndash; to prototype, ideate, and get a hands-on sense of the physics of robots.</description></item><item><title>Octopus-Inspired Soft Hydrogel Robots</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/onr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/onr/</guid><description>&lt;div class="text-center">
&lt;img src="https://idealab.asu.edu/assets/images/research/onr1.png" width="50%">
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We are working to create a framework for design, rapid prototyping and control of robust, energy-efficient, autonomous soft arms with octopus-inspired distributed neuromuscular sensing and actuation. The arms will be capable of continuous deformation through the use of hydrogel &amp;ldquo;muscles&amp;rdquo; and distributed sensing through the use of embedded silver &amp;ldquo;neuron&amp;rdquo; interconnections. Such a unique octopus-inspired design forms a built-in local &amp;ldquo;sensing-actuation&amp;rdquo; feedback loop to achieve adaptive reconfiguration in response to the local environment. Such local adaptation will enable the robot to perform high-level tasks such as locomotion and reversible adhesion without coordination from a central controller in a highly accurate, rapid, and energy-efficient way. This study will also produce fundamental principles and theory for the modeling and control of soft robots in a way which leverages their unique capabilities and is inspired by how cephalopod appendages interact with their environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Efficiency of Spine Stiffness in regards to Anguilliform Locomotion</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/anson-kwan-thesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/anson-kwan-thesis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fish come in varying shapes, sizes, and ecosystems that lead to a multitude of different modes of swimming. To categorizes these different methods, fish are separated by fin and body motion. In particular the order of fish Anguilliformes or ‘eel-like’ locomotion utilizes a large portion of their body to produce thrust while swimming known as undulatory locomotion [1]. Due to the developments of high-speed video capture, research with in the past two decades have been able to understand eel locomotion, kinematics, and hydrodynamics. These results have given us more accurate models for Anguilliformes and data about the efficiency, stiffness, and kinematics of their swimming behaviors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low-Cost Hands-On Engineering Projects and Curriculum for Elementary School Level Children</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/jade-heun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/jade-heun/</guid><description>&lt;p>Elementary students have had a harder time staying engaged in the material during class time, especially since the start of Covid, whether they are online or in-person. Due to the virus, schools require there be enough materials for each individual student to work with so that they can all participate in the activity. Since the schools and teachers generally do not get enough funding, the teachers have to resort to doing the activity themselves under the document camera. Hands-on activities generally help keep the students involved in the curriculum and help them to remember what they have learned. In order to make sure every student can have their own materials, the project kits need to be low-cost and easily accessible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congrats to Anson Kwan</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2022-03-28-congrats-to-anson-kwan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2022-03-28-congrats-to-anson-kwan/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congrats to Anson Kwan, who recently defended his Barrett Honors Thesis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congratulations to Mohammad Sharifzadeh and Yuhao Jiang</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2022-02-15-icra-submissions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2022-02-15-icra-submissions/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dr. Mohammad Sharifzadeh and Doctoral Student Yuhao Jiang just got their paper accepted to ICRA 2022. We&amp;rsquo;ll see you there in May!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharifzadeh, M., Jiang, Y., Salimi Lafmejani, A., &amp;amp; Aukes, D. (2022). Compensating for Material Deformation in Foldable Robots via Deep Learning &amp;ndash; A Case Study. 2022 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)(Accepted).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DREAMS/CPAR Seminar</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2022-01-17-dreams-cpar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2022-01-17-dreams-cpar/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dr. Aukes recently presented recent work at the DREAMS/CPAR Seminar at Berkeley.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://citris-uc.org/event/dreams-cpar-seminar-daniel-aukes/">https://citris-uc.org/event/dreams-cpar-seminar-daniel-aukes/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recent Presentation by Dr. Aukes</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2021-12-12-dr-aukes-presentation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2021-12-12-dr-aukes-presentation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dr. Aukes recently presented some recent work at the ATLAS Institute. This has just been posted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.colorado.edu/atlas/atlas-colloquium">https://www.colorado.edu/atlas/atlas-colloquium&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congrats to Anson Kwan</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2021-07-01-congrats-to-roozbeh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2021-07-01-congrats-to-roozbeh/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congrats to Roozbeh Khodambashi, who recently defended his PhD Thesis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congrats to Mohammad Sharifzadeh</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2021-06-01-congrats-to-mohammad-sharifzadeh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2021-06-01-congrats-to-mohammad-sharifzadeh/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congrats to Mohammad Sharifzadeh, who recently defended his PhD Thesis&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Origami-Inspired Testing Platform Research Assistant</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2021-04-01-summer-internship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2021-04-01-summer-internship/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are seeking research assistants to work 10 hours per week in the IDEAlab on the Poly campus. This project will focus on developing a testing platform built on the Robotic Operating System (ROS) for testing various foldable robots with a number of different integrated hardware solutions. The project will require familiarity with Python, Linux, serial and ethernet-based communication protocols.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal is that by the end of the summer, numerous systems will be communicating and controlled over a ROS-based network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Paper on Hydrogels</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2021-01-25-new-paper-on-hydrogels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2021-01-25-new-paper-on-hydrogels/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congrats to Roozbeh Khodambashi and the rest of our research team for our new paper in Advanced Materials.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/adma.202005906">https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/adma.202005906&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://fullcircle.asu.edu/research/behaving-like-animals/">https://fullcircle.asu.edu/research/behaving-like-animals/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IDEAlab featured in Full Circle</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-10-15-idealab-featured-in-full-circle---copy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-10-15-idealab-featured-in-full-circle---copy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cole Brauer and Dr. Aukes were featured in a recent post on ASU&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://fullcircle.asu.edu/students/more-program-funds-research-for-masters-students/">Full Circle&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ASU Receives 15 CAREER awards</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-07-15-asu-receives-15-career-awards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-07-15-asu-receives-15-career-awards/</guid><description>&lt;p>The IDEAlab is hiring for multiple positions in Wearable Robotics. See details &lt;a href="%7B%7Bsite.base_path%7D%7D/hiring">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Congrats to Cole Brauer</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-03-24-congrats-to-cole-brauer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-03-24-congrats-to-cole-brauer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Congrats to Cole Brauer, the recipient of the Dean&amp;rsquo;s Fellowship, and the newest of the IDEAlab&amp;rsquo;s PhD researchers!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Professor Aukes Featured</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-03-19-professor-aukes-featured/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-03-19-professor-aukes-featured/</guid><description>&lt;p>Professor Aukes has been featured in &lt;a href="https://fullcircle.engineering.asu.edu/faculty/making-robots-accessible-to-all/">Full Circle&lt;/a> for the recent news regarding his Career Award!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="%7B%7Bsite.base_path%7D%7D/press">Press&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="%7B%7Bsite.base_path%7D%7D/projects">Projects&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SWRS 2020 Cancelled</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-03-15-swrs-2020-cancelled/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-03-15-swrs-2020-cancelled/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are sorry to say that the SWRS 2020 is cancelled. Check &lt;a href="http://swrobotics.engineering.asu.edu">here&lt;/a> for more information as it unfolds&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Symposium on Computational Fabrication</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-03-04-symposium-on-computational-fabrication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-03-04-symposium-on-computational-fabrication/</guid><description>&lt;p>Consider submitting to the Symposium on Computational Fabrication. Deadline April 10&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://scf.acm.org">https://scf.acm.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New NSF Program in Robotics</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-02-28-new-nsf-program-on-robotics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-02-28-new-nsf-program-on-robotics/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are excited about the new Foundational Robotics program at NSF with regard to robotics!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://nsf.gov/pubs/2020/nsf20051/nsf20051.jsp">link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foldable Robotics Fall 2020</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-02-25-foldable-robotics-fall-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-02-25-foldable-robotics-fall-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>Foldable Robotics will be taught in Fall 2020! More info &lt;a href="http://idealab.asu.edu/teaching/foldable-robotics-f-2020">here&lt;/a> as it develops&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Southwest Robotics Symposium 2020</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-02-21-southwest-robotics-symposium-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2020-02-21-southwest-robotics-symposium-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are excited to be a part of the &lt;a href="http://swrobotics.engineering.asu.edu">2020 Southwest Robotics Symposium&lt;/a>
Please consider submitting a poster or attending April 2-3 in Mesa, AZ!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foldable Robotics</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2019-12-16-foldable-robotics-iii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2019-12-16-foldable-robotics-iii/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please visit back for details soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Travel Funding Options for Students</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2019-04-20-travel-funding-options-for-students/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2019-04-20-travel-funding-options-for-students/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here is the graduate student travel funding request form/information.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: left">Resource&lt;/th>
 &lt;th style="text-align: left">Link&lt;/th>
 &lt;th style="text-align: left">Details&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">Graduate &amp;amp; Professional Student Association (GPSA)&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;a href="https://gpsa.asu.edu/funding/">link&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">For graduate students.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">Travel Grant Program&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;a href="https://undergraduate-research.engineering.asu.edu/travel-grant-program/">link&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">Undergraduates&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">Barrett Honors College&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">N/A&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">Visit Barrett&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">FURI&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;a href="https://undergraduate-research.engineering.asu.edu/travel-grant-program/">link&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">For students who participated in FURI&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">Graduate College&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;a href="https://graduate.asu.edu/pay-for-college/travel-awards">link&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">For Graduate Students&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">KEEN Student Mini Grants&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;a href="https://entrepreneurship.engineering.asu.edu/kern-asu-student-funding-opportunities/">link&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">Poly&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;a href="%7B%7Bsite.base_path%7D%7D/assets/tps-student-travel-form.pdf">Form&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">Email form to &lt;a href="amy.wolsey@asu.edu">amy.wolsey@asu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>EGR598:Foldable Robotics</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-10-23-foldable-robotics-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-10-23-foldable-robotics-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>Professor Aukes will be teaching an EGR598 class this Spring called &lt;em>Foldable Robotics&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Foldable Robotics&lt;/em> is a class which comes from a new class of active robotic devices being developed in research labs across the country. These devices are designed and built using flat sheets of a wide variety of materials, and folded up to create both form and motion. This class studies these devices from initial prototype and design through implementation and optimization, with a focus on application-specific projects which seek to solve problems of cost, parallelism, complexity, and time with a relatively fast and easy prototyping method.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Keen Professorship</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-05-16-keen-professorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-05-16-keen-professorship/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dr. Aukes has been named a 2017 Keen Professor! This award, presented by the Kern Foundation, is given faculty members who propose novel ideas in teaching with an entrepreneurial focus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two Papers Accepted!</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-05-01-two-papers-accepted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-05-01-two-papers-accepted/</guid><description>&lt;p>We have had two papers recently accepted!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[1] K. Luck, J. Campbell, M. Jansen, D. M. Aukes, and H. Ben Amor, “From the Lab to the Desert : Fast Prototyping and Learning of Robot Locomotion,” in Robotics: Science and Systems Conference, 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2] A. Jansen, K. S. Luck, J. Campbell, H. Ben Amor, and D. M. Aukes, “Bio-inspired Robot Design Considering Load-bearing and Kinematic Ontogeny of Chelonioidea Sea Turtles,” in Living Machines, 2017, pp. 1–12.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Night of the Open Door</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-02-17-night-of-the-open-door/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-02-17-night-of-the-open-door/</guid><description>&lt;div class="embed-responsive embed-responsive-4by3">
&lt;iframe class="embed-responsive-item" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/204797330" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/204797330">Night of the Open Door: Polytechnic Campus&lt;/a> from &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/asu">Arizona State University&lt;/a> on &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
[ASU Now Link](https://asunow.asu.edu/20170219-sun-devil-life-asu-night-open-door-polytechnic-thunderbird-campuses?utm_campaign=SFMC_Now-022017_ASU%20Now&amp;utm_medium=email)</description></item><item><title>The Origami Revolution</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-02-11-the-origami-revolution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-02-11-the-origami-revolution/</guid><description>&lt;p>Prof. Aukes will be featured in &lt;a href="http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/nova/physics/origami-revolution.html">&lt;em>The Origami Revolution&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, airing on PBS Feb 15!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting Agenda</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-01-05-lab-meeting-agenda/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2017-01-05-lab-meeting-agenda/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="topics">Topics&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Wiki / CMS / Slack / collaboration tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>reference management&lt;/li>
&lt;li>conference planning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>equipment and materials purchases&lt;/li>
&lt;li>computers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>documentation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="upcoming-training">Upcoming Training&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>laser cutter &amp;amp; laminates manufacturing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>python &amp;amp; codebase&lt;/li>
&lt;li>dynamics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fea&lt;/li>
&lt;li>markdown, jekyll, &amp;amp; latex integration&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="misc">misc&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>lynda&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="presentation-dan-lab-overview">Presentation: Dan Lab Overview&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>IDEAlab at IROS</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2016-10-15-iros-presence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2016-10-15-iros-presence/</guid><description>&lt;p>Professor Aukes gave a talk at the &lt;a href="http://idealab.asu.edu/foldable_robotics/">&amp;ldquo;Folding in Robotics&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> workshop at IROS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>National Robotics Week at Poly</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2016-04-01-national-robotics-week/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2016-04-01-national-robotics-week/</guid><description>&lt;p>The robotics group at The Polytechnic School just hosted several busloads of kids during their annual DiscoverE day on campus, as well as a public open house on Friday, April 1 2016. Thanks to all for coming!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IDEAlab at ICRA</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2016-03-21-icra-presence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2016-03-21-icra-presence/</guid><description>&lt;p>Professor Aukes will be at ICRA, May 16-20. He will be available to consult with anyone interested in using popupCAD and/or building laminate devices. You can email him at danaukes-at-asu.edu to schedule an appointment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foldable Robotics</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2016-03-10-foldable-robotics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/news/2016-03-10-foldable-robotics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Professor Aukes will be teaching a new EGR598 class this fall called &lt;em>Foldable Robotics&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="row">
&lt;div class="col-sm-6">
&lt;p>&lt;em>Foldable Robotics&lt;/em> is a class which comes from a new class of active robotic devices being developed in research labs across the country. These devices are designed and built using flat sheets of a wide variety of materials, and folded up to create both form and motion. This class studies these devices from initial prototype and design through implementation and optimization, with a focus on application-specific projects which seek to solve problems of cost, parallelism, complexity, and time with a relatively fast and easy prototyping method.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A foldable quad-copter for enhanced maneuverability</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/foldable-drone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/foldable-drone/</guid><description>&lt;!--TODO: Finish--></description></item><item><title>Balancing Quadruped</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/dante-roush/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/dante-roush/</guid><description>I am expanding the work done by previous Master’s Student Ben Shuch in the field of Quadrupedal Robotic Locomotion. I am utilizing force sensing to calculate the center of balance of a quadrupedal laminate robot with the end goal of implementing a controls system capable of adapting in real time to changing ground angles. Each of the robot’s four legs have two degrees of freedom and are controlled by a four-bar system powered by two servo motors. While standing in place, the robot will behave like a parallel manipulator; when standing on an angled table, it will use the difference between the current force distribution and an ideal force distribution for balance to direct a change in leg length to counteract the angled ground. The laminate materials used to construct the robot make it a more cost effective research platform for researching controls problems.</description></item><item><title>Bio-inspired bipedal robot design</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/sudhanshu-kataray/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/sudhanshu-kataray/</guid><description>&lt;p>My research draws inspiration from terrestrial avians in terms of development of an optimized leg design for bipedal walking, running and jumping. I will be applying the skills I have learned during the foldable robotics class in the estimation of kinematics, design and fabrication of the robotic leg using software such as Python and SolidWorks. To gauge the dynamics of the leg for different functions I will be using Unity Simulation Engine and Visual Studio to validate the results of experimental testing and biomechanics research. My team has already created a model for the leg which we will begin to conduct experiments on. I have used Unity to help test motor parameters in order to select a motor with the best combination of gear ratios, masses and torques for our leg design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Buoyancy Control of a Bio-inspired Robotic Fish</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/alia-gilbert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/alia-gilbert/</guid><description>This project focuses on controlling the altitude of an underwater robot meant to do environmental cleanup of vegetation in a canal. A bladder modeled off fish anatomy will be designed containing two bulbs, likely of laminate material, with a tube containing a pump. The pump will transfer air between the two bulbs to control the direction of the buoyancy in the robot. The shift in buoyancy will allow the body of the robot to move either up or down. Using this laminate material in prototyping for underwater robotics allows for low cost testing and quick turnaround time for iterations. We will be checking consistency of the level that the robot is driving using an IMU to control the amount of water or air in the bulbs of the systems.</description></item><item><title>Calendar</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/calendar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/calendar/</guid><description>&lt;iframe src="https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?height=600&amp;amp;wkst=1&amp;amp;bgcolor=%23ffffff&amp;amp;ctz=America%2FPhoenix&amp;amp;src=YXN1LmVkdV9iaTV0MDVvbTg0amx0NDN1cGhmc2RscHRwMEBncm91cC5jYWxlbmRhci5nb29nbGUuY29t&amp;amp;src=aDA0NTc4YXUxZzhuYnRpcDk4anNwMXZlbmNAZ3JvdXAuY2FsZW5kYXIuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbQ&amp;amp;src=YXN1LmVkdV84aTlhZHVxdmI4YjhsaHFvaW1xMWZiazAyZ0Bncm91cC5jYWxlbmRhci5nb29nbGUuY29t&amp;amp;src=ZW4udXNhI2hvbGlkYXlAZ3JvdXAudi5jYWxlbmRhci5nb29nbGUuY29t&amp;amp;color=%23795548&amp;amp;color=%237CB342&amp;amp;color=%238E24AA&amp;amp;color=%230B8043&amp;amp;mode=WEEK&amp;amp;showTitle=0&amp;amp;showNav=1&amp;amp;showPrint=0" style="border-width:0" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0" scrolling="no">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://calendar.google.com/calendar/selfsched?sstoken=UUczUW5BTnJwQlktfGRlZmF1bHR8MWJkYjgxMDFjOTYxZTRjODNkNjZjODMwOTY0MGUwNDE">Schedule an appointment&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;!--Add yourself to the [IDEAlab-info](https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/idealab-info) listserv to stay up to date on meeting times and location changes.-->
&lt;p>Check out Dr. Aukes&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href="https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/aukes_calendar/">calendar&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Canal Maintenance and Cleaning via Autonomous Fish-Inspired Robots</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/srp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/srp/</guid><description>&lt;!--
image: /assets/images/research/fish1.png

title: 'Phase I: Laminate Robot Platform to Facilitate Autonomous Canal Maintenance'
title: 'Phase II: Navigation and Control of an Autonomous Fish-Inspired Robot for
 Canal Cleaning and Maintenance'
-->
&lt;p>In this project, the goal is to build an AUV that explores the water canals and performs cleaning of these canals as necessary. We have selected the fin propulsion mechanism as the propulsion system for our AUV. Essentially, we are designing and building an underwater robot that will use a fin to move inside water. Our capability of using a laminated robot, will give us more advantage in easily gain the required stiffness in the tail in order to overcome the water drag.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children’s Engineering Kit</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/hebellyn-quezada/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/hebellyn-quezada/</guid><description>The purpose of this project is to create a kit that aims to spark an interest in engineering for preadolescents and investigate what are effective methods of doing so. The highlight of this project is the implementation of Choice Theory, which proposes that student engagement increases when they are presented with a series of options to choose from. The kit will consist of lessons that diverge in different directions on multiple steps to represent the diversity of engineering solutions. In the end, these branched out paths will merge together to a single product to show students the interconnectedness of different engineering disciplines. The students’ interaction and completion of the kit will be analyzed to determine what level of complexity and guidance is best suited for preadolescents.</description></item><item><title>Contact and Location</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/contact-and-location/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/contact-and-location/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="contact">Contact&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please send all inquiries to &lt;a href="mailto:danaukes@asu.edu">danaukes@asu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="row">
&lt;div class="col-md-4">
&lt;h2>Locations&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3>Office&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
Santa Catalina, Room 331C&lt;br>
7271 E Sonoran Arroyo Mall&lt;br>
Mesa, AZ 85212
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Lab&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
Technology Center, Room 180&lt;br>
6075 Innovation Way West&lt;br>
Mesa, AZ 85212
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="col-md-8">
&lt;h2>Map&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/embed?mid=1c0SlwOpM4YpWklAyhv0seTeWpaaLkBI&amp;ehbc=2E312F" width="640" height="480">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Control of a biped laminate robot</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/taha-shafa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/taha-shafa/</guid><description>Currently, a lot of focus previously for laminate robots has been on design, but more complex applications require higher level design. The aim of my project is to demonstrate that laminate robots can be utilized for higher level design by designing a laminate biped with model-based controls that can balance while standing and walking. This project starts from the early
prototyping design stage. Designs are created using python and Solidworks; PopupCAD is used to produce the DXF files needed for high speed laminate manufacturing. Through testing various design iterations, a design was reached with the ability to stand. The motors of this design were then modified to meet desired torque parameters. Testing has shown high torque is necessary to utilize robust control techniques, which will be used to balance the biped while it both stands and walks. Through python-based physics simulations utilizing Kane’s method, a model of the bipedal design can be created and linearized for controls applications. Since the system is fully controllable, LQR control techniques will be applied for balancing while standing and walking. Eventually, different control systems can be design and implemented for various system applications.</description></item><item><title>Daniel M. Aukes, PhD</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/people/dan-aukes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/people/dan-aukes/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://idealab.asu.edu/assets/images/headshots/aukes.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="mailto://danaukes@asu.edu">danaukes@asu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="">CV&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/aukes_calendar">Calendar&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daniel M. Aukes is an Associate Professor at Arizona State University, and is the Principal Investigator of the IDEAlab. His research investigates the nexus of design, manufacturing, and data-driven decision-making towards the development of robots that can operate in niche environments, with a focus on affordability and accessibility. He is a former Technology Development Fellow at the Wyss Institute at Harvard University and completed post-doctoral research in the Harvard MicroRobotics Lab with Rob Wood, developing manufacturing planning software for origami-inspired robots. Dr. Aukes received his PhD and Masters degrees in Mechanical Engineering from Stanford University, studying the design of underactuated robotics hands under Mark Cutkosky. He received his BS in Mechanical Engineering from Northwestern University. Dr. Aukes’s industry experiences have focused on manufacturing automation across a wide range of industries including automotive, pharmaceutical, and food-processing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Design of a Cutting Tool for Clearing Underwater Vegetation</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/sheena-benson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/sheena-benson/</guid><description>The objective of this research is to further the development of the bio-inspired fish being and constructed by Dr. Aukes and his team of student researchers by designing an inexpensive, reliable, and effective cutting tool to be used in conjunction with the robotic fish to cut and reduce the number of underwater vegetation growing in canals and waterways here in Phoenix. Such a device would reduce the cost and manpower currently used to clear those canals. Without clearing aquatic plants from the canals, certain parts of the city would also become vulnerable to increased flooding in the event of a sudden downpour, leading to possible infrastructure damage.</description></item><item><title>Design of a Hopping Platform using Laminate Construction</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/jacob-knaup-hopping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/jacob-knaup-hopping/</guid><description>Taking advantage of laminate materials&amp;rsquo; flexibility, a high-performance jumping platform is developed. A physical prototype and accurate model of the design are sought in tandem with each being used to inform the other. This will result in a leg design to be incorporated into future jumping or hopping robots and a validated simulation that can be used to design future robots using the same methods.</description></item><item><title>Design, Implementation, and Testing of a Force-Sensing Quadrupedal Laminate Robot</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/ben-shuch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/ben-shuch/</guid><description>In this project we present a low-cost force-sensing quadrupedal laminate robot platform. The robot has two degrees of freedom on each of four independent legs, allowing for a variety of motion trajectories to be created at each leg, thus creating a rich control space to explore on a relatively low-cost robot. This platform will allow a user to research complex motion and gait analysis control questions, and use different concepts in computer science and control theory methods to permit it to walk. The motion trajectory of each leg has been modeled in Python. Critical design considerations are the complexity of the laminate design, the rigidity of the materials of which the laminate is constructed, the accuracy of the transmission to control each leg, and the design of the force sensing legs.</description></item><item><title>Development and Validation of a Custom Soft-Body FEA Simulator for Rapid Prototyping</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/erick-duarte/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/erick-duarte/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="descriprion">Descriprion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>How reliable are the forces generated by a simulation of a soft hydrogel robot when compared to a real-life counterpart&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hydrogels are water-swollen three-dimensional polymeric networks that respond to specific stimuli, such as electrical signals, magnetic fields, mechanical stress, light, or temperature1. These stimuli cause a controllable change in the shape or volume of the hydrogel, physically altering the molecular interactions
in the material. Voxels represent a value on a regular grid in three-dimensional space. Similarly to a pixel with an added dimension, and just like pixels, voxels can be used to make shapes and structures. Voxels allow the user to create discrete packages of material that perform predictably
and are easy to use. Hydrogel can technically be cast into many shapes and sizes, but using uniform cubes simplifies changes in the design, especially when many
iterations are expected.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Development of an Multi-Process Planning Tool</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/cole-brauer-manufacturing-planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/cole-brauer-manufacturing-planning/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project seeks to provide methods and set of tools for processing, modifying, and generating 3D models that use multiple materials and fabrication processes. Areas of research include planning of fabrication steps, automatic part modification, optimization of component properties, and generation of the
files and fixtures needed to produce multi-material parts. Implementation of these algorithms is done in Python using a voxel-based model representation. This work will make multi-material fabrication more accessible for educational and research robotics. Current work is focused on applications of graded materials in the design of robust material transitions. The results will inform the design of stronger flexible joints for use in low-cost robotics applications. More information is available on the project &lt;a href="https://github.com/cdbrauer/VoxelFuse">GitHub repository&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downloads</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/download/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/download/</guid><description>&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: left">Item&lt;/th>
 &lt;th style="text-align: left">CAD&lt;/th>
 &lt;th style="text-align: left">Controller&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">Quadruped&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;a href="">link&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: left">&lt;a href="">link&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Equipment and Facilities</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/equipment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/equipment/</guid><description>&lt;p>The IDEAlab at Arizona State University&amp;rsquo;s Polytechnic School has a wide variety of equipment available for designing, prototyping, modeling, analyzing, simulating, and testing a variety of robotic devices made using less-traditional materials.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prototyping laminate robotic devices involves several planar processes which are available within the lab, including cutting, alignment, and lamination. We are capable of cutting a variety of flat, rolled, or sheet materials on either a Vinyl Express R31 Vinyl Cutter or an Epilog Fusion M2 CO2/Fiber Laser Cutter with a 28&amp;quot; x 40&amp;quot; bed. Lamination is made possible via a ProMount Plus 2700 27&amp;quot; Heated Roll Mounting Laminator, a 16&amp;quot; X 24&amp;quot; Giantex Digital Clamshell Heat Press, a wide-frame, floor mounted impulse sealer, and a small craft iron for detailed work. Larger format materials can be cut out on a 4&amp;rsquo; x 8&amp;rsquo; ShopBot Router located in the Polytechnic Schools&amp;rsquo; Innovation Hub.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Extending the Jumping Range of a Small Robot via Collapsible Gliding Wings</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/guston-lighthouse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/guston-lighthouse/</guid><description>This project investigates the impact curvature, buckling, and anisotropy play when used passively to enhance jumping capability. In this project we employ a curved structure to allow a rigid link to collapse preferentially in one direction when it encounters aerodynamic drag forces. A model was constructed in Python using the data gathered through the experiments and was tuned so that its outputs were as close as possible to the experimental results. As expected, increasing the wing diameter increased the total fall time, and increasing the payload mass decreased the total fall time. Orientation of the wings around the vertical axis of the glider relative to the direction of horizontal motion was also found to have an effect on the length of time between when the gliding platform was launched and when it made contact with the ground, with a configuration where the axis between the wings was parallel to the direction of motion granting added stability.</description></item><item><title>Foldable Robotic Elephant Trunk</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/mannat-rana/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/mannat-rana/</guid><description>Standard robotic arms are limited by their cost, size, and lack of flexibility. These factors make standard robotic arms difficult to apply in complex scenarios. While traditional, rigid robotic arms are used in factories and plants, they require meticulous planning, spacious locations, heavy funding, and can only be used for limited purposes, as they are inherently unsafe around humans. Laminate devices, on the other hand, are far more compact, flexible, cheap, and modular, as they use flat, somewhat flexible materials which fold up like a popup-book to create complex nonlinear motion. With these advantages in mind, I propose to research continuum robot arms made using foldable, laminate techniques, using an elephant trunk as a source of inspiration. The elephant trunk has more degrees of freedom than the standard robotic arm, which allows it to perform complex manipulation tasks in unstructured natural environments. This concept, when applied to a robotic arm, would allow it to be used in many more applications, and could be designed to accomplish a variety of tasks ill-suited to typical robot arms. Furthermore, the system could be designed to be collapsible, which would make it modular, portable, and easily deployable, increasing its applications further.</description></item><item><title>Foldable Robotics 2024</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-robotics-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/foldable-robotics-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="quadruped.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-info">Key Info&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fall 2024 Semester&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RAS 557 #86916&lt;/li>
&lt;li>M/W, 9:00 am-10:15 am&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peralta 103&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://catalog.apps.asu.edu/catalog/classes/classlist?campusOrOnlineSelection=A&amp;amp;catalogNbr=557&amp;amp;honors=F&amp;amp;promod=F&amp;amp;searchType=all&amp;amp;subject=RAS&amp;amp;term=2247#detailsOpen=86916-131772">Course Info &amp;amp; Registration&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="topics">Topics&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Kinematics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dynamics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Design&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Manufacturing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Robotics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Programming in Python&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simulation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Hiring</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/hiring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/hiring/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are currently not hiring at this time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting Schedule</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/meeting-schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/meeting-schedule/</guid><description>&lt;iframe width="100%" height="600px" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRsWjRYwN4B5g0DcBZdQ4oqBRIyTpDRmRPIZOyZWbqXxxWB6aPa0Dp6kqyMtDD5q1TMMcd4S4oB7V1N/pubhtml?gid=0&amp;amp;single=true&amp;amp;widget=true&amp;amp;headers=false">&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>Low-Cost, Modular Force Control Solution</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/jacob-knaup-force-sensing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/jacob-knaup-force-sensing/</guid><description>Force control offers numerous benefits to robots over other control schemes such as more natural movements and increased sensitivity to the surrounding environment, but it is typically only available to high-end robots. This research aims to develop a modular force control solution for low-cost robots. The solution is designed to be easy to incorporate into future laminate robots, allowing the designer to add force control capabilities, while placing minimal constraints on the design.</description></item><item><title>Modular Tail for Stabilizing Robot Platforms</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/frank-onoye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/frank-onoye/</guid><description>Based on the idea that robots can be made to display many features of animals such as locomotion, the goal of this thesis is to recreate a tail based on the mechanics of a cheetah since the use of its tail is the most effective in dynamic stability and test its effectiveness on an inherently unstable object such as an rc car. The question focuses on which tail design is necessary to fix an inherently unstable object. This topic is derived from how a cheetah uses its tail to stabilize itself while catching prey. The question of developing  a design will be answered by creating a unity model inspired by a cheetah’s tail and simulate how it will stabilize an object that lacks balance. The selected platform is an rc car. The model is already developed in unity, but its movement is not unstable. After making the inherently unstable by adjusting the scaling of the object to make it taller, the motor speed, turning angle, mass of the cube, mass of the wheels, and radius of the wheels, a motor and tail will be added for balance. The selected rc car will be adjusted to match the parameters in unity. The expected result of this procedure is to have a display of a real life model matching the simulation.</description></item><item><title>Professor Aukes' Calendar</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/aukes_calendar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/aukes_calendar/</guid><description>&lt;div class="embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9">
&lt;iframe src="https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?height=600&amp;wkst=1&amp;bgcolor=%23ffffff&amp;ctz=America%2FPhoenix&amp;showTitle=0&amp;showPrint=0&amp;mode=WEEK&amp;showCalendars=0&amp;src=ZGFuYXVrZXNAZ21haWwuY29t&amp;src=bTBmaGZicTkxZmpsYjdwMHBkZGQ2bjFnc2NAZ3JvdXAuY2FsZW5kYXIuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbQ&amp;src=YXN1LmVkdV9iaTV0MDVvbTg0amx0NDN1cGhmc2RscHRwMEBncm91cC5jYWxlbmRhci5nb29nbGUuY29t&amp;src=OGkxM2k1ZnZmNGVsaGR2Z3U5dDA5Y2piZzBAZ3JvdXAuY2FsZW5kYXIuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbQ&amp;src=dGpqYXRwMWJsZTVoMzk3Y2VjY3JnYW1jYjRAZ3JvdXAuY2FsZW5kYXIuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbQ&amp;src=ZGF1a2VzQGFzdS5lZHU&amp;color=%23F09300&amp;color=%234285F4&amp;color=%23795548&amp;color=%23D50000&amp;color=%23C0CA33&amp;color=%23F09300" style="border-width:0" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0" scrolling="no">&lt;/iframe>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/publications/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="journal-articles">Journal articles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[1] D. Li, D. M. Aukes, E. Q. Y. Aukes, and W. Zhang, “A Compact, Lightweight, Fast-Responding and High-Torque Mechanical Lockable Robot Module,” (submitted), 2024.
[2] Y. Jiang, F. Chen, and D. M. Aukes, “Locomotion via Vibration of Soft, Twisted Beams with an Under-actuated Quadruped,” (submitted), 2024.
[3] F. Chen, “Curating Tunable, Compliant Legs for Specialized Tasks,” (submitted), 2024.
[4] Y. Jiang, F. Chen, and D. M. Aukes, “Tunable Dynamic Walking via Soft Twisted Beam Vibration,” IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, 2023, doi: 10.1109/LRA.2023.3244716.
[5] Emiliano Quinones Yumbla, Dongting Li, Tolemy M. Nibi, Daniel M. Aukes, and Wenlong Zhang, “A Kinematically Constrained Kalman Filter for Sensor Fusion in a Wearable Origami Robot,” Letters Dyn. Sys. Control, 2023, doi: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4056986">https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4056986&lt;/a>.
[6] F. Chen and D. Aukes, “Direct Encoding of Tunable Stiffness into an Origami-inspired Jumping Robot Leg,” Journal of Mechanisms and Robotics, pp. 1–28, Feb. 2023, doi: 10.1115/1.4056958.
[7] C. Brauer and D. Aukes, “Applying graded material transitions with low-cost additive manufacturing,” RPJ, vol. 29, no. 2, pp. 378–392, Jan. 2023, doi: 10.1108/RPJ-04-2022-0114.
[8] H. Bagheri et al., “A Bio-inspired Helically Driven Self-Burrowing Robot,” Acta Geotechnica (accepted), 2023, doi: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11440-023-01882-9">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11440-023-01882-9&lt;/a>.
[9] D. Li et al., “Origami-Inspired Wearable Robot for Trunk Support,” IEEE/ASME Transactions on Mechatronics, pp. 1–11, 2022, doi: 10.1109/TMECH.2022.3220136.
[10] M. Sharifzadeh, Y. Jiang, A. S. Lafmejani, K. Nichols, and D. Aukes, “Maneuverable gait selection for a novel fish-inspired robot using a CMA-ES-assisted workflow,” Bioinspiration &amp;amp; Biomimetics, vol. 16, no. 5, p. 056017, Sep. 2021, doi: 10.1088/1748-3190/ac165d.
[11] M. Sharifzadeh, Y. Jiang, and D. M. Aukes, “Reconfigurable Curved Beams for Selectable Swimming Gaits in an Underwater Robot,” IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, vol. 6, no. 2, pp. 3437–3444, Apr. 2021, doi: 10.1109/LRA.2021.3063961.
[12] M. Sharifzadeh and D. M. Aukes, “Curvature-Induced Buckling for Flapping-Wing Vehicles,” IEEE/ASME Transactions on Mechatronics, vol. 26, no. 1, pp. 503–514, 2021, doi: 10.1109/TMECH.2020.3034659.
[13] C.-Y. Lo et al., “Highly stretchable self-sensing actuator based on conductive photothermally-responsive hydrogel,” Materials Today, vol. 50, pp. 35–43, Jun. 2021, doi: 10.1016/j.mattod.2021.05.008.
[14] D. Li, S. Huang, Y. Tang, H. Marvi, J. Tao, and D. Aukes, “Compliant Fins for Locomotion in Granular Media,” IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, 2021, doi: 10.1109/LRA.2021.3084877.
[15] R. Khodambashi et al., “Heterogeneous Hydrogel Structures with Spatiotemporal Reconfigurability using Addressable and Tunable Voxels,” Advanced Materials, vol. 33, no. 10, p. 2005906, Mar. 2021, doi: 10.1002/adma.202005906.
[16] A. Doroudchi, R. Khodambashi, M. Sharifzadeh, D. Li, S. Berman, and D. M. Aukes, “Tracking Control of a Miniature 2-DOF Manipulator With Hydrogel Actuators,” IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, vol. 6, no. 3, pp. 4774–4781, Jul. 2021, doi: 10.1109/LRA.2021.3067622.
[17] Y. Alsaid et al., “Tunable Sponge‐Like Hierarchically Porous Hydrogels with Simultaneously Enhanced Diffusivity and Mechanical Properties,” Advanced Materials, vol. 33, no. 20, p. 2008235, May 2021, doi: 10.1002/adma.202008235.
[18] O. Mesa, S. Mhatre, and D. Aukes, “CREASE: Synchronous gait by minimizing actuation through folded geometry,” International Journal of Architectural Computing, vol. 18, no. 4, pp. 385–403, Dec. 2020, doi: 10.1177/1478077120948204.
[19] A. S. Lafmejani et al., “Kinematic Modeling and Trajectory Tracking Control of an Octopus-Inspired Hyper-Redundant Robot,” IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, vol. 5, no. 2, pp. 3460–3467, Apr. 2020, doi: 10.1109/LRA.2020.2976328.
[20] S. Huang et al., “Effects of Friction Anisotropy on Upward Burrowing Behavior of Soft Robots in Granular Materials,” Advanced Intelligent Systems, p. 1900183, Feb. 2020, doi: 10.1002/aisy.201900183.
[21] H. Bagheri et al., “New Insights on the Control and Function of Octopus Suckers,” Advanced Intelligent Systems, p. 1900154, Feb. 2020, doi: 10.1002/aisy.201900154.
[22] S. M. Felton, K. P. Becker, D. M. Aukes, and R. J. Wood, “Self-folding with shape memory composites at the millimeter scale,” Journal of Micromechanics and Microengineering, vol. 25, no. 8, p. 085004, Aug. 2015, doi: 10.1088/0960-1317/25/8/085004.
[23] M. T. Tolley, S. M. Felton, S. Miyashita, D. Aukes, D. Rus, and R. J. Wood, “Self-folding origami: shape memory composites activated by uniform heating,” Smart Materials and Structures, vol. 23, no. 9, p. 94006, Sep. 2014, doi: 10.1088/0964-1726/23/9/094006.
[24] D. M. Aukes et al., “Design and testing of a selectively compliant underactuated hand,” The International Journal of Robotics Research, vol. 33, no. 5, pp. 721–735, Apr. 2014, doi: 10.1177/0278364913518997.
[25] D. M. Aukes, B. Goldberg, M. R. Cutkosky, and R. J. Wood, “An analytic framework for developing inherently-manufacturable pop-up laminate devices,” Smart Materials and Structures, vol. 23, no. 9, p. 094013, Sep. 2014, doi: 10.1088/0964-1726/23/9/094013.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Research Opportunities</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/research-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/research-opportunities/</guid><description>&lt;p>The IDEAlab at ASU is always looking for researchers in the field of robotics, design, and manufacturing. Get involved by coming to lab meetings and assisting on one of our existing projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="phd-research">PhD Research&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please see our &lt;a href="%7B%7Bsite.base_path%7D%7D/hiring">hiring&lt;/a> page for current openings&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="masters-research">Masters Research&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The IDEAlab doe not generally fund masters research, but there are opportunities to complete course credit or apply for external funding through the IDEAlab&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="more">MORE&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The MORE Initiative is a unique opportunity to get involved in research during your masters experience, &lt;em>and get a small stipend to do so.&lt;/em>. In general, planning for your application involves identifying a research topic of interest, speaking with Dr. Aukes to ensure it fits within the scope of the IDEAlab, and coming up with the deliverables required by the FURI program. &lt;em>Please see Dr. Aukes at the beginning of the semester in order to plan your MORE application.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seminar</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/seminar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/lab-info/seminar/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are announcing a new workshop series aimed at graduate students looking to improve their technical proficiency in the field of robotics for research and industry, as well as to get to know their fellow RAS students a little better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stop by (in-person) next Friday, Oct 4 for the first session. Details and RSVP link are below, poster is attached.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Friday, October 4
Polytechnic Campus
Peralta 135
1-2pm&lt;/p>
&lt;p>for any questions, please contact me, &lt;a href="mailto:danaukes@asu.edu">danaukes@asu.edu&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Signals in the Soil</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/sits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/sits/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s inside the ground leaves us a mystery, and we are trying to use the self-boring robot nodes to collect signals underground. Currently, we are focusing on the soft material-granular media contacting behavior, adding material compliance into granular media RFT model. With a sand-burrowing robot platform built, we are validating the model, adding sensors, and implementing control. As a final goal, a series of self-burrowing digging robots will be created, enabling us to sense underground environments with minimal human intervention.</description></item><item><title>Testing Method of Stiffening Actuators</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/anson-kwan-furi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/anson-kwan-furi/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="objective--research-question">Objective &amp;amp; Research Question&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The goal of this project is to design a platform that can evaluate the performance of wearable robotic prototypes designed to stiffen on command for the purpose support and stabilization.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Millions of elderly adults around the world experience
loss of stability which can lead to falls and injury&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A wearable hybrid robotic system has been proposed to
assist and support elderly users via a variety of potential
prototyped solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Being able to model the dynamic performance is
essential to understanding these protypes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The purpose of this test platform is to provide a generic
interface to understand more about these designs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="methods">Methods:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Based off data collected from motion capture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Torque = 80.0 Nm&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Angular Velocity = 2.75 rad/s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Power = 150 W&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Test actuators need to be able to achieve similar performance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Design parameters that are available to change include motor selection, gear selection and lever arm lengths.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="results">Results&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A rotary based test bench is proposed due to its decreased friction with in the system as well as its adaptability for future testing of multiple actuators with
multiple degrees of freedom&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CIM was selected for the use of test bench with 70:1 gear reduction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Future work will include obtaining and integrating components and developing a test protocol to implementation into Python&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Underactuated Laminate gripper with Low-Cost Sensing.</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/drew-carlson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/drew-carlson/</guid><description>This project explores the design and development of a robotic gripper using low cost materials. It uses a four-bar mechanism to grasp objects. The system is back driven until the finger makes contact with an object. The servo continues to drive over coming the force of a spring holding the gripper in a open position providing the method of under-actuation. The laminate design allows for multiple materials to be used. This can be exploited to make the contact points more flexible for the inclusion of flex sensors. By using multiple low cost flex sensors the location, number, and amount of force being applied in the grip can be determined using beam theory as a model.</description></item><item><title>Wing Design</title><link>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/vipul-gadekar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://idealab.asu.edu/projects/archive/vipul-gadekar/</guid><description>&lt;p>The projects involve design of wings for a laminate biped robot for providing locomotion stabilization. The wings are designed to provide stabilization for different gait such as running, hopping and jumping. The project aims to develop a reliable dynamics model which includes biped dynamics as well as aerodynamics for creating and testing multiple designs optimized for various gaits. The aerodynamic simulations are run on a vortex-lattice code \u201CVORLAX\u201D, which provides numeric simulation of the defined geometric bodies. The simulations are then to be plugged into the robot dynamics model, which is to be utilized for robot design iterations, simulations and design of a controller. &amp;quot;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>